What's going on everyone? This is James with the
School of Hard Knocks. I'm here with Jack and Josh.
We've got a crazy busy day planned today. We're going
to go get some grub and then we're going to be
going all around downtown Austin to
interview some multi-millionaires. You know, stay tuned
for today and tonight we're going to be
going out downtown again, down to 6th Street
to film part two, video number
two for After Hours for the new
channel that we've been growing. So, you know, let's
just, let's get after it today and I can't wait
to deliver this content for you guys. Let's get it.
Music
You know, what's your name and where are you from?
My name's Elliot Hill and I live here in Austin.
What industry did you decide to
pursue a career in? I sold sneakers
and t-shirts for a living. No way.
So did you own your own company?
No, I worked for Nike. You worked for Nike? Yeah.
And what were you doing exactly? I did a little bit
of everything from sales to retail
to product. I was ultimately the president
of the company. Of Nike? Yeah. No
way. Way. You were the president of Nike?
Yeah. Oh my goodness. That's amazing. That's
why I saw the white whites there.
Do I know Phil Knight? Yeah. Yeah,
I know him real well. Wow. That's amazing.
So as someone who's been an entrepreneur, what is
your best piece of advice to someone starting a business
in 2022? Super strong focus on the consumer. So like
who are you trying to
serve and what type of problems?
Are you trying to solve for those people or what
type of products are you trying to create for them?
But I think it all starts
with having a really super strong focus
on the consumer you're trying to serve. So
for someone who's been a president and has overseen
a company like Nike, what have
you seen throughout Nike that's really
enabled them to really grow and scale their
brand? I guess, what is your advice to someone
trying to scale and grow their brand and
build a business into like a renowned name
like Nike today? Well, I think
what great companies do, not just Nike,
but great companies. It comes back to what I've
already said. It's the consumer in the case of
Nike was athletes. We served athletes. We listened
to those athletes and the insights that they gave
us, we translated into innovative product that
people coveted and desired and wanted. And we
told really emotional, cool stories that connected the
consumer to the brand and to those products.
And so I guess NetNet is super sharp focus
on the consumer. That then translates into a great
product. And then you've got to tell emotional stories.
What would you say has been your secret to
sales in 2022? A lot of people are scared to go
out and ask and you've walked up to me and said,
Hey, can I talk to you? You got to be bold.
You got to be confident. You got to stand up and ask
people for the order. So anyway, absolutely. Thank you
so much for your time. Have a great day.
Thank you. Just got back from Better Halves
and now we're here in downtown Austin and crazy,
just ran into the former president of
Nike, got to know him a little bit,
find out about his business.
Story downtown, going to go talk to some more
people and find out about them and, you know,
just ask them questions again on what's, you
know, made them so successful and help them
throughout their careers. What industry did you
guys pursue a career in? Finance. I'm in
finance business. How can someone become
financially free in 2022? Honesty, transparency,
honesty with yourself. You know, I think people
today get caught up too much in social media.
Remember what it's really about. It's about
yourself, not what other people think about,
you know,
I think that people look
at social media too much, honestly.
And do you think as far as like a
skill set that people should be looking to obtain,
whether it's a soft skill or hard skill that
you've seen has really helped people kind of grow and
separate themselves from other people in the business world?
Communication, ability to communicate, get out of your comfort
zone, talk to someone, do like this, you know,
be open with someone. Yeah, that's the most important
thing really, because you can use that for anything.
Absolutely. Get out of your own way. Yeah,
get out of your own way. That's good.
Do you guys think a college degree is
necessary to be successful in today's society? No.
Why not? I don't. I really
don't. We have a kid in school.
Yeah, I mean, we have a
daughter. Our youngest is in college.
Our two older picked a different route
and we picked, he went to college.
I didn't. Debatable subject always. I think it doesn't hurt.
I think it's good, but I don't
think it's the end all be all.
I think if you talk to most millionaires today, I
don't think most of them went to college or finished college.
Depends what you want to do. If you want
to be an attorney, you got to go to school.
Yeah, or a doctor. Yeah.
If you just want to be successful, no,
you don't have to go to college for that.
Excuse me, gentlemen, question for you guys.
If you were to go back to when you were in either high school
or college, what is the best piece of advice you tell your younger self?
Go into marketing. Why marketing?
Because that's a great skill to have.
What industry? Business. I'm in engineering.
Engineering. Yeah.
How can someone become financially free in 2022?
Invest. Save 10%, 15% of your paycheck.
Try to try to put that.
Pay down your debt first.
If you were having a conversation with your younger self coming
out of high school, what would you tell your younger self?
And maybe that. I think I would have invested more in real estate and stocks and stuff rather than
just putting in like leaving it in cash and things like that or spending it on trips and stuff.
But I mean, obviously you want to
have a good time and you're young.
That's so. But you still want to have maybe some
targets, right, to shoot for so you put that away.
Absolutely.
Okay.
Excuse me, sir.
Yeah.
Question for you.
If you were to go back to when you're in either high school
or college, what is the best piece of advice you tell your younger self?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Y'all school hard knocks?
Yes, sir.
I've seen.
I feel like I've done this before.
Yeah.
Right.
So y'all really have some time
to really sit down and talk.
You have about 30 minutes of your time.
Let's do it.
We're down.
Well, follow me this way.
Let's go.
Let's do it.
Yeah.
You're not growing.
You're not.
I guess.
What do you think is like made Austin such a capital for that kind
of growth for technology and all these businesses to come out here and flourish?
I think it's the laid back attitude of everyone.
I think one of the coolest things about Austin that I noticed is that in Austin
you get this more authentic, you know, kind of, you know, lifestyle, which I really like.
You know, people aren't afraid to be them.
So.
Obviously, guys.
You know, crazy spot here.
You know, one of the probably probably one of
the coolest apartments I've ever been to in Austin.
Yeah.
Wow.
No, this is this is crazy.
Yeah.
Wow.
This is unreal.
For those of you who
don't know, this is Lavon Perrin.
And one of the coolest things about Lavon and us is that
last year around August, we actually asked him to do an interview.
Just let me just read you off.
Some of these statistics real quick.
We did an interview with Lavon and the video itself got two
point three million views, three thousand comments, thirty thousand saves, seventy thousand shares.
Not only did it blow up on Tik Tok, but it also got over
a million views on Twitter and was honestly one of our favorite interviews we've done.
Got so many messages about it.
Where did you start out?
What industry are you in now and
what plans if you have in the future?
Couple of industries I was in, you know,
I started off with MCI back in the day.
A lot of y'all don't know what that is.
A lot of y'all don't understand.
You used to have to pay for long distance.
So I started off with that.
Selling long distance was very successful.
One of the youngest supervisors there won many awards.
So I bounced around, started my own business.
I was actually a private driver,
drove around a couple of celebrities.
Then COVID hit.
And then that's when things changed.
So I decided whether I was going to get back in insurance like I've done before or was
I going to simply, you know, go maybe real estate because it was really booming at the time.
So I went ahead and got back into insurance.
Through insurance.
I got back into the real estate business.
I've been able to, you know, be successful, hire people, teach them how to help protect families and just move up
the ladder and move up the scale and, you know, be one of the best new writers they've seen in a while.
And just, you know, start growing my business and growing
my pipeline that way and finding something that you're passionate about.
Something where you can get paid for what you're worth.
In my case, I was being in
business for myself, but not by myself.
This skyscraper balcony apartment.
And it's, I mean, one of
the best views I've ever seen.
In the city.
A lot of younger people aspire to be able
to own and live in a place like this.
You know, as a business owner, what has been that thing throughout your
lifetime that's been a constant factor that's enabled you to, you know, be successful?
The belief I've always had in my mind that
I can be and do anything I want to do.
That belief and sometimes blind ambition that you just go
for some things and kind of figure it out later.
What I did then is just
really start looking at the numbers.
Go for it and see what you find.
Some of that has helped me not
be scared, not to be afraid to approach.
Things.
What is the difference between like whole life and term life policies and which one
should people really be looking to get for themselves when they're looking to make that investment?
Well, that's a great question.
And it's an argument that's been around forever.
Almost like what came first, the chicken or the egg?
The truth of the matter is
you actually probably should lean toward both.
So let me explain to
you what I mean by that.
First of all, a term
plan is just like it sounds.
It starts at a certain point
and ends at a certain point.
Let's say if it's a 30 year term.
You simply make your pay.
The payments stay the same for the
entire term for 30 years, 360 payments.
And it's ended at.
Usually you don't really have any more coverage left.
But the benefits for that is because if I'm a younger person, I have family and I have kids, I'm going to get the
more bang for my buck to make sure that house is paid off while the kids are young and something happens for younger people.
Depends on their situation.
Term is really fits them at the time as you get older and you mature kids
out of the house, things of that nature or even before they're out of the house.
But when you're trying to plan for that
whole life may be a little bit better.
Now, a lot of people think the term is cheaper.
Right.
And part of the reason why it appears to
be cheaper is because the premium you pay every month.
However, when you did it with whole life, it appears
to cost more money because you pay more money every month.
But the part that a lot of people
are missing is the understanding you pay more money.
That's because part of the money that you put
into a whole life is actually invested on your behalf.
So if you look at a whole life plan, that money is that you put in and invest
it is equal amount of money that you put in over that particular term on the long run.
Whole life is cheaper.
Even.
Though you pay more money per month.
So neither one of them are bad.
Right.
It just depends on where you are
in your your life and what you need.
How important is it for young people
to at least try to pursue their dreams?
There's no practice life.
It's not always about what you
do to get to your goal.
A lot of times people
want to work in their passion.
If you can work in your
passion and be successful, that's great.
But also you can work something else that makes
you the money so you can live in your passion.
So when you're young.
And you don't have too many ties.
It's a lot easier for you
to get out and try stuff.
Travel.
Put together money.
Save money.
Just depends on your goal
and your drive and your why.
If you don't quit, you don't lose.
A lot of people have been going on our website.
SFG Austin dot com is our website.
You can look at all
the things we have to offer.
We also hire from that website.
Also, you can actually get
coverage yourself on that website.
I work with with a
company that allows me to have.
30 different carriers I can do business with.
That separates me from a lot of companies.
Because if someone has a certain ailment or they were diabetic
before the age of 50 or had any kind of health issues.
Some companies may not cover them.
But because I have 30
different companies I can choose from.
I can take the time to
find what works for the customer.
Also, what works for their budget instead of
just giving them one solution to their problem.
All the companies we use are over
100 years old and they're A rated.
So those are some of the things we
do and how we're able to be successful.
It's just.
Really helping others.
The impact you make on others is
going to determine how successful you are.